你干嘛呢
What are you doing?
吃麦圈
Eating cereal.
我烤了一只鸡
I got us a chicken for dinner.
鸡
Chicken.
真的吗
Seriously?
你现在肯定不饿了
You're not gonna be hungry now.
你又做错了
Oh, you're doing it all wrong again, as usual.
我没有  我从纵隔膜开始切
I'm not.I'm cutting from the mediastinum out.
你不戴眼镜根本看不见纵隔膜在哪
You can't even see the mediastinum without your glasses.
该死  我的眼镜呢?
Damn it.Where are my glasses?
放下吧
No, put it down.
放下
Down.
在这
Right here.
就在这
Mm. Right here.
走开
Move.
没有你我可怎么办
What would I do without you?
饿死
Starve.
不幸的女孩
A damsel in distress.
连上监视器  预约床边胸片
Put her on a monitor.Order a portable chest.
我给你开刀
I'm gonna cut your top off.
在我第九肋和第十肋之间
It's between my ninth and tenth intercostal spaces.
没有出血  没有气胸
There's no hemo or pneumothorax.
我的生命体征稳定  直接拔出来就成
My vitals are stable.Just pull it out.
-不成  -该干嘛干嘛去
-i wouldn't.  -mind your own business.
这是谁?
Who is this guy?
把这东西拿出来
Get this thing out of me.
我今天已经在主任面前搞砸过一次
I already screwed up in front of the chief today once.
我不能
I can't...
缝合砸了  再让他看见  一定比第12名还讨厌我
I mess up a suture, and now he's looking at me like I'm number 12.
梅瑞  拜托了  别让任何人看见我这样
Mer, please.No one gets to see me like this, okay?
杨  到底怎么回事
Yang... What the hell happened?
-给她连上监视器  预约床边胸片  -做完了
-get her on a monitor and order a portable chest.  -i did.
-检查呼吸功能了吗  -查过了
-did you check her respiratory function--i did.
看见了?
See?
-呼气清晰均匀  -你别说话
-breath sounds clear and equal. -you be quiet.
格蕾  如果这是医疗教学  你有什么建议?
Grey, what would you advise as a course of treatment?
我觉得要等到
I think we should leave it in until
胸片和CT出来才可以
We get the chest x-ray and the c.T.Back
我很好
I'm fine.
感染呢?
But what about infection?
冰锥肯定把脏水带进身体里了
This thing is definitely melting dirty roof water into her body
我们应该把它拔出来
Which is why we should pull it out.
别碰它
Leave it right where it is.
胸腔被刺穿  你还能呼吸算很走运了
You get stabbed in the chest and you're lucky enough totill be breathing,
别拔冰锥  弄清楚里面是什么再操作
You leave the knife in,
弄清楚里面是什么再操作
At least until you figure out what's going on inside
留在里面
Leave it in.
-拿出来  -留在里面
-take it out.  -leave it in.
你什么都知道
In the meantime, since you know so much,
那你来给实习生下医嘱吧
You can teach your interns how to treat you
这是复习基础的好机会
This is a good opportunityto get back to the basics.
但我得去检查文森特 坎纳
But I need to check on Vincent Kenner.
格蕾  现在你负责文森特 坎纳
Grey, vincent Kenner is your responsibility now.
记住  他是我的病人
But bear in mind, he is my patient,
我今天不想再因为外伤死人
And I'm not about to lose another trauma case today
让他活下去
Keep that man alive.
我能跟你说句话吗  亨特医生?
Can I get a word with you, dr. Hunt?
你觉得能留住她的记忆?
You think you'll be able to restore her memory?
我能把血抽干净  减除压力
Well, i was able to suction the blood and remove the pressure.
我满怀信心  虽不确定  但有信心
I'm hopeful.Not certain, but hopeful.
15号刀
15-blade, please.
怎么了  谢博德医生?
Something wrong, dr. Shepherd?
哦  天
Oh, my god.
汉娜医生之前跟我说过教学的事情
Dr. Hahn asked me about teaching before.
记住  当你递刀时
Here's a tip--when you Hand a surgeon
要确定刀柄朝前
A 15-blade, make sure it's Handle first
把血吸干净  我去清洗一下  换副手套
Suction the bleeders while I clean this up and get a new glove.
他真的会好起来吗
He's really gonna be okay?
除了他的声带
Except for his voice.
他的腹部已经软多了
His abdomen's definitely more tender.
还需要做个CT
He needs another c.T
迈克尔  医保出问题  对吧
Michael, the insurance, it's--it's a mistake, right?
是出错了
It's gotta be a mistake.
写下名字和号码
Look, write down a name and number,
我来处理  一切都会好的
And I'll fix it, and everytng will be fine, right
都会好起来  对吧
Everything's gonna be fine?
一会儿再写吧
Uh, maybe later would be better.
来吧
Come on, honey.
怎么了
What's going on?
我们要试试低温治疗
We're going ahead with the freezing.
不经过我同意?
Without my consent?
不  我不同意
No, i don't think so.
你是个医生  怎能不尽全力
You really want to be the doctor who doesn't give his all to keep a man
让病人下半生免受轮椅之苦呢
From being wheelchair-bound for the rest of his life?
滚出我病人的病房
Get out of my patient's room!
我可不听平民使唤
I don't take orders from civilians.
-听着  你个高傲的小...  -谢博德
-listen, you arrogant, little  -shepherd.
现在病人很稳定
Okay, right now this patient is stable.
他或许永远不能走路
He may never walk again, but if you try this,
低温治疗可能导致血栓  器官衰竭  死亡
He could throw a clot, go into organ failure, and he could die
我们已经决定低温治疗
We're going ahead with the freezing.
从今天一早开始
Ever since this morning, you've been pissing on
为了证明第12  你谁都不放过
Anything with a pulse trying to prove you're not number 12
你确实不是第12
And you're not.
但你能做这种事  你就是个排12的
But right now, with this decision, you act like number 12.
祝你手术成功  托瑞斯医生
Good luck with the patient, dr. Torres.
主任简直鬼上身了
You know, the chief is under the spell of some insane man in camouflage.
我病人的命是他救的
He saved my patient's life.
虽然哑了  但命保住了
He'll never talk again, but still, life saved.
你手怎么了?
What happened to your Hand?
手术刀割的
Ah, scalpel.
柔思弄的
Rose.
不是故意的
Not intentional.
她现在就像厨房的死老鼠
She's a dead mouse on the kitchen floor.
该让它消失了
At some point, you gotta pick it up and throw it away.
我帮你看看?
Want me to take a look at that?
有梅瑞帮我看
Mer's gonna take care of it.
我可是著名整形医师  格蕾只是个住院
I'm a renowned plastic surgeon.Grey's a resident.
她还和我上床呢  特别是我受伤时
She gives me sex, especially when I'm wounded.
是这个位置吧?
Is this positioned right?
又不是查乳腺!
If I'm getting a mammogram.
低一点  往右
Lower, to the right.
你俩干吗呢?
Two, what are you doing?
盖块布  挡住你的"那里"
Uh, draping so your parts are safe.
离我"那里"远点
Get away from my parts.
轻点  轻点
Oh, gentle, gentle, gentle.
怎么样啊?
How are you doing?
求你给我拍片吧  实习生太白痴
Please take my films, 'cause my interns are idiots.
坎纳先生怎么样?
How's mr.Kenner?
-稳定下来了 但...  -千万别把他弄死啊
-well, he's stable, but  -you cannot let him die.
我尽量  别动
I'm doing my best.Hold still.
没动  赶紧拍
I am.Just shoot it.
别动  我有话问你
Hold still because I want to ask you a question.
什么?
What?
关于我和德里克  你是认真的?
Did you mean what you said about me and Derek?
你怎么这样
Oh, well, this is not fair.
-人家都被刺穿了...  -我知道自己唠叨
-i'm impaled a  -i know I talk about it too much,
知道自己变得又软弱  又黏人  又肉麻
And I know I've gone soft and gooey and disgusting.
我自己听了都想吐
And if I had to listen to it, i'd puke, too.
但你那都是气话
But you said what you said because you
不是真的  对吧?
Were mad, right, not because you meant it
你就给我拍片子吧
Can you just--just take my x-ray?
我的话不重要
And--and it doesn't matter what I say.
当然重要!
Of course it matters what you say!
当然很重要!
Of course it matters.
不许照!
You stop--oh!
不许拍照!  赶紧拍片子!
Stop taking my picture and take my picture!
感觉好点吗?
Are you feeling okay?
她还不知道  自己的生活要乱套了
Her world is about to fall apart, and she has no idea.
都是我的错
It's all my fault.
我该怎么办?
What should I do?
我知道自己很坏  可该怎么办呢?
I know I'm a terrible person, but what should I do?
你该自己告诉她
She should hear it from you.
你是她最好的朋友  再坏的事
You're her best friend, even if it's the most terrible thing in the world,
也该由你告诉她
You should tell her.
凯丽马上做冰冻治疗  去看吗?
Callie's gonna freeze her patient.You want to go check it out?
怎么不理我?
Why are you ignoring me?
我指望你唠叨够了
I'm hoping if I wait long enough, you'll be as
然后能被自己的声音厌烦之后自己闭嘴
Annoyed by the sound of your voice as I am and just shut up
好吧
Okay.
我怎么惹你了?
Did I do something?
-你自己清楚  -我不清楚
-you know what you did.  -no, i don't.
阿历克斯  到底怎么了?  我以为...
Alex, just tell me.What did I do?I thought that--
闭嘴  那晚我很难受  哭得像个娘们
Just shut up.I had a bad night and I cried like a girl.
我想通了  你也得想通
I'm over it.You need to get over it, too.
给你输冰盐水
That chill you'll feel is the cold saline rushing
降低体温  你会觉得冷
Through your veins to lower your core body temperature
要是成功  我就能走路了?
And if it works, i walk?
如果成功  应该可以的
If it works, the hope is that you walk.
真好
Okay, uh...
真的很冷
I'm--i'm getting cold.
体温还是96.8华氏度
He's temp's still 96.8
主任  要不要再加条冰毯?
Chief.Shall we lay another cooling blanket on him?
由你决定  托瑞斯医生
That's up to you, dr. Torres.
你是主刀
You're taking point.
排名第一的教学医院主任就这么做
That's what the chief of a number one teaching hospital does.
疑人不用  用人不疑
He Handpicks talented surgeons and lets them take point.
是吧  贝利医生?
Right, dr. Bailey?
完全正确  主任
Couldn't agree more, chief.
温暖舒适  我很温暖舒适
Warm and toasty, that's what I'm feeling.
脉搏下降
His pulse is falling.
-你确定...  -降到52了
-are you sure  -yeah, down to 52.
心率降低是正常的
Yeah, it's normal for his pulse to fall.
还要多久?
Okay, h-how much longer we got?
马上就好
Not too much longer, okay?
你做得很棒
You're doing great.
继续想着温暖舒适
Keep thinking warm and toasty.
我尽量啊
Okay.I'm trying.
很好
Good.
排第12  死去吧
Number 12, my ass.
知道我怎么割到手的吗?
You want to hear how I cut my Hand?
很精彩
It's a good story.
同居的事  是不是先缓一缓
I am not sure moving in together is a good idea.
好
Okay.
行
Fine.
行?
Fine?
什么意思?
What does that mean?
意思是  我了解你
It means that I know you.
什么意思?
So what, you didn't believe that I
你早就料到我会反悔?
Would let you move in in the first place
我料到你会认为我这么想
I believe that you believe it.
我会慢慢来  一步一步  不冒进
Look, i'm gonna move very slowly-- baby steps, no sudden moves.
你和树林里的小鹿一样
You're like a deerin the woods.
好吧  是我用蜡烛摆出一个房子
Okay, i built the house of candles.
那可是梅瑞狄斯史上破天荒的
That is unprecedented in the Meredith chronicles.
行啊  那就同居吧
Fine.Let's move in together.
行
Fine.
除非你想直接结婚?
Unless, of course, you just want to go ahead and get married.
上当了吧
Gottcha
知道我和谁学的?
You want to know where I learned that?
要从割伤手指说起
Goes with the story of how I cut my Hand.
你和阿历克斯说了什么?
What did you say to Alex?
没有啊
I-i didn't say anything.
我就说很高兴你俩又和好了
I just s-said that I think it's nice that you two are friendly again.
讨厌  梅瑞狄斯  别人的事你能不能别管?
Oh, damn it, meredith.Why can't you just mind your own business?
算了  怪我不该告诉你
You know what?Forget it.I should never have told you anything.
除了克里斯蒂娜  谁的秘密你都守不住
You can't keep anything to yourself unless it's for Cristina.
结婚吧?
Marriage?
一点都不好玩
Not funny.
贝利医生
Dr. Bailey.
嗯
Yeah.
迈克尔 贝利尔  腹部软下来了
Michael Briar's abdomen is more tender.
我知道该先做CT
Now i-i know I'm supposed to get a c.T.
但如果零点以后手术  保险就过期了
, but if we start the surgery after midnight, he's not covered.
他等于就破产了
We're basically bankrupting him.
我看  是不是就不做CT了
I say we skip the c.T.
你看?  你看不了  你只能问
Oh, you s--you say?No, you don't say.You ask.
回答是  不能为了省钱违规操作
And the answer is, we don't skimp on medicine to save money.
做CT去
Gethe c.T.
菲利普  你做得很棒  我给你镇静剂加量
Phillip, you're doing great.I'm giving you more sedative
再加点麻醉剂  就不会抖了  好不好?
And a paralytic to stop your shivering, okay?
好  好
Okay, okay.
插管吧  贝利
Okay, we'll need to intubate, bailey.
好  放下来
All right, coming down.
1  2  3  放
One, two and three and down.
降到华氏90度了
He's down to 90 degrees.
好像...太低了
I think that's, um, too low.
太低了吧?
I-is that too low?
是你查过资料的
You did all the research.
我觉得太低了
I think it's too low.
天哪
Oh, my god.
现在怎么办?
Okay, so what now?
怎么解决?
Is this gonna resolve?
注射利多卡因还是胺碘达隆?
Do they recommend lido or amiodarone?
托瑞斯医生?
Dr. Torres?
Uh, dr.Torres?
测不到脉搏了
He's barely got a pulse.
该做心肺复苏了吧?
Uh, uh, should we do c.P.R.?
不行  谢博德刚做了椎管减压  不能压他
No, he--let's t-try to avoid jostling Shepherd's spinal decompression
除非万不得已
Unless absolutely necessary.
完了
Oh, crap.Crap.
他快没心跳了
His heart is likely to stop, soon.
你要怎么处理  托瑞斯医生?
What are you gonna do, dr. Torres?
我不知道
I don't know.
我...我不知道
I-i don't know.
他怎么样了?
How is he?
我们给他用药  保持血压
We've given him medication to keep his blood pressure up,
但是贝蒂的丈夫情况不尽人意
But Betty's husband's not as stable as we'd like him to be.
他们要低温治疗菲利普...
They're freezing Phillip...
低温...
Freezing him...
来帮助他恢复行走
To try to help him walk again.
我不... 他们解释得很清楚
I don't... They explained it to me very well.
贝蒂颅脑手术
And Betty's having surgery on her brain,
可怜的文森特生命垂危
And poor Vincent here is barely Hanging on..
-而迈克尔...  -没事的
-and Michael...  -it's all right.
我们会挺过来的
We'll survive.
我们总会挺过来的
We always do.
我只希望他能看着我
I wish he would just look at me.
迈克尔八个月前失业了
Michael lost his job eight mohs ago.
什么?
What?
公司让他走人
The firm let him go.
他只是...
He just...
他没法告诉你
He couldn't bring himself to tell you.
他觉得很失败
He--he just felt like such a failure.
为什么... 我不...为什么你...你怎么知道的?
Why--i don't--wh-why do you--how do you know this?
他对你说的
He told you.
他对你说了
你和我丈夫上过床吗?
Have you been sleeping with my husband?
-我非常...  -室颤  蓝色警报!
-i'm s--he's in v-fib.Code blue!
请让她们出去
Get them out of here, please.
-这是怎么了?  -一单位去甲肾上腺素和阿托品
What--push one of epi, one of atropine.
你开始做体外循环了?
You started him on ecmo?
把血抽出来再输回去?
You're taking out all his blood and replacing it?
这是唯一的出路  汉娜医生
It was the only thing to do, dr. Hahn.
我们不想动脊椎  这样可以减轻心脏负担
We don't want to jostle his spine, and this will give his heart some rest.
他苏醒之前  我们需要你密切观察
Now we need you to monitor him until we get him back on.
你到底加入吗?
Now are you in or not?
我把迈克尔送去做CT了
I sent Michael down for the c.T.
我希望能在最后期限前进手术室
I was hoping we could, uh, start the surgery, get him in under the wire,
但已近子夜了  所以...
But it's almost midnight, so...
无关紧要  我不在乎  不在乎
It doesn't matter.I don't care.I don't.
贝蒂的丈夫怎么样了  你知道吗?
Do you--do you know anything about Betty's husband?He...
我觉得他快不行了...
I-i think he was dying.
你...有没有消息?
Do you--have you heard anything?
没有  没听说什么
No.I-i can find out.
男人为什么出轨?
Why do men cheat?
我丈夫和我朋友上床
My husband slept with my friend.
他失业了  然后还和我朋友搞上了
He lost his job, and then he slept with my
却还一直说爱我
Friend, all the while telling me he loves me
为什么?
Why?
或许是因为身陷低谷
Maybe he was low.
他很沮丧  不想让你看到他这样  痛苦  萎靡
He was down, and he didn't want you to see him like that, in pain, weak...
不像个男人
As less than a man.
他有自尊心  所以他选择逃避
He has his pride, so, uh, he turned away.
这样不对  但...
It's not right, but it...
这不代表他不在乎你
It doesn't mean he doesn't care about you.
我可以保证
I swear it doesn't.
好了  停止体外循环吧?
All right, we all ready to wean?
开始吧
Let's do it.
他似乎心跳过速
It looks like he's tachycardic.
做电复律吗?  还是上腺苷?
Should we shock him, give him adenosine?
一般情况下没错  但这人像个冰块
Well, normally I'd say yes, but this man's an ice cube.
托瑞斯医生  在你的研究里面
Dr. Torres, in any of your research,
想一想有没有说出现类似情况该怎么做?
Was there anything to suggest what to do in a situation like this
我不  我不...  我是说...
I don't--i don't-- I mean, um...
我觉得  我搞砸了
I think I messed up here.
我是说  我不知道  可能... 也许...
I mean, i don't know.I mean, maybe--maybe--maybe
他会不治自愈
He would've been fine on his own.
-可能  或许...  -好 看着我
-maybe--maybe--all right, look at me.Look at me.
集中精力
Focus.
你是在创新
You're trying something new.
创新没有错
There's nothing wrong with new.
开天辟地  拓宽边界  都需要魄力
Breaking new ground, pushing the boundaries, it comes with the job.
托瑞斯医生  深呼吸  别紧张  说吧
So, dr. Torres, take a breath, stop panicking and just tell us.
你研究出什么?
What did your research say?
研究表明...
My research showed that...
达到某种阈值时会出现心律失常
Arrhythmias can occur at a certain threshold.
皮温在华氏91.5度到92度之间
His appear to be between.. Uh, 91.5 and 92 degrees.
他现在在90度左右
He around 90 right now.
好的  那...
Okay, so...
我们可以用体外循环帮助他复苏
We could use the ecmo to help bring him back up.
是  但不能太快  它本身也会出问题
Yes, but not too quickly, because that can cause problems of its own.
好的  看来我们得加加温了
All right.Looks like we have some warming to do.
看出什么来了?
What do you see?
看起来好像什么都没刺中?
Um, it kinda looks like it's hitting nothing?
没刺中?
It looks like it's hitting nothing?
因为就是什么都没刺中!
Because it's hitting nothing!
这是什么意思呢?
So, like, what does that--at does that mean?
你又是什么意思啊?
What do you mean, what does that mean?
你连X光片都不会看吗?
Don't you know how to read an x-ray?
向来都是你看的
You--you always read them.
出去
Well, get out.
全都给我...
All of you just...
出去!  找个有大脑的人来
Get out and find me someone with a brain.
他们是你的实习生?
Those your interns?
他们好像很怕你
They seem pretty scared of you.
我不可怕
I am not scary.
你想干吗?
Uh, what are you doing?
是冰锥
That's my icicle.
没错
Yeah.
你拔了冰锥
Uh, you took out my icicle.
我没批准呢
I didn't give you permission to do that.
那又怎样?
So?
他死了
He died.
我的病人还活着吗?
My patient still alive?
情况稳定
He's stable.
你听军医的话
You let some soldier off the street talk
结果差点害死他
You into something that could have killed a man
那是他应得的康复机会
He deserved the chance.
我们不知道结果如何
We have no way of knowing if it helped
他理应得此机会  德里克
Or hurt. -he deserved the chance, derek
我们理应为他提供最全最好的帮助
He deserved the best, the most that this hospital could give him.
过去几年我回避了太多
I've let a lot of things slide over the past few years.
我一直很...软弱
I've been... Soft.
不是软弱不软弱的问题
This was not about you being soft.
是啊  我想是因为梅瑞狄斯在这儿
Yeah, i think it's the fact that Meredith's
她是爱丽丝的女儿
Here, the fact that Ellis' daughter is here
主任
Chief.
文森特 坎纳  输了31单位的血  都是冷冻血浆
Vincent Kenner--we gave him 31 units of blood, fresh frozen plasma
几升林格氏液
, multiple liters of l.R.
我们竭尽所能
We did everything we knew how to do.
却回天乏术
We just couldn't bring him back.
你们根本一无所知...
You don't know how to do anything...
谁都一样
None of you.
住院医师两年才过一半
You're halfway through your second year of residency,
你四处晃悠
And you walk around this hospital
觉得心安理得
Like it's your god-given right to be her
不是的  格蕾医生
Well, it is not, dr. Grey.
我可以保证
I assure you.
你在这里  是因为我
You are here because I allow it.
你在这儿替我办事  我就让你办了这一件事
You are here to do what I say, and the one thing I ask you to do-
-你却救不活...  -理查德
-you can't even save--richard.
我们救不了所有人
We can't save everybody.
我们没尽全力
We should try harder.
迈克尔 塞拉贝丝来了
Michael, sarabeth is here.
他有点体力不支
He's a little tired.
从CT上看  他的血肿越来越严重
Uh, the c.T. Showed that his hematoma's getting worse.
我和贝利医生马上就推他进手术室
So dr. Bailey and I will be taking him down to the o.R. Soon.
不过他给你写了封信
But he wrote you, um, this letter.
我没兴趣
I'm not interested.
"塞拉贝丝" 对不起
"sarabeth." sorry.
不是我说的  是信
Um, that wasn't me, that was the letter.
这个...
It...
我... 我知道你恨我
"i-i know you hate me.
也不是我  是信  我读给你听吧
"um, again, it's not me, it's the letter.I'll--i'm just gonna read.
我知道你现在恨我入骨
Um, i know you hate me right now."
恨也是应该的
"and you have every right to.
我背叛了你
"i betrayed you.
背叛了我们的婚姻
I betrayed our marriage.
我失业了  却无法对你开口  我告诉了安娜
"but I had lost my job and I couldn't tell you, "so I told Anna instead, "
这是个愚蠢的错误
Which was wrong and stupid.
千万次  我都想告诉你
"and I've wanted to tell you a million
我真的很抱歉
Times "and let you know how truly sorry I am,
可我现在口不能言
But now I have no voice.
我求你  恳求你用心听我的话
"so I am begging you, please, if you could justisten with your heart.
这真有诗意
"oh, that is so poetic.
这句话是我说的  不是他写的...对不起
That--that was me, so--not him.Sorry.
如果你在用心听  我跟你坦白时...
Um, if--if you could just listen with your heart ""when I tell you that"
我知道你不会立刻原谅我
I know you can't forgive me right now "but I'm
但我愿倾尽全力补偿你
Gonna do everything in my power to make it up to you
无论发生了什么事  你怎样决定
"and no matter what happens, "no matter what you decide to do
我依然会爱着你  直到世界末日
I'm gonna love you until the end of time.
就那么多  我的说话完了  他说完了
"that's it.-i'm done talk-well, he's done.
这个就是结尾了
It's the end.
她还没醒  你愿意的话我可以带你去见她
She's not awake yet,  but I can take you to see her if you'd like.
-她还能记得住东西?  -我们还不清楚
-and her memory?  -we don't know yet.
别
Oh,  no.
不要说出来
Oh,  please don't say it.
对不起  文森特
I'm sorry. Vincent.
-噢  天啊  -噢  主啊  别这样  别
Oh,  god. Oh,  god,  no,  no.
我感到非常抱歉
I'm very sorry.
-塞拉贝丝  -别  别  别  不要过来
-sarabeth.  -no,  don't,  don't. Just don't.
文森特去世了  还有贝蒂...
Vincent's dead,  and Betty...
我们不知道她能不能撑过来  菲利普跟迈克尔...
We don't know if she's gonna be okay,  and-and Phillip and Michael-
别跟我提他名字!
Don't you mention his name to me.
今天的倒霉事都赶到一起了
More bad things have happened to us today than have ever happened before.
在此之前我们都很幸福  我受之泰然
We have been blessed until today. I took it for granted.
我把你当做理所应当
I took you for granted.
我们从儿时到现在  交情已有50年了
We've been friends for 50 years,  ever since we were little girls.
我犯了一个很糟糕的错误...
And I made...One awful,  awful mistake...
可我不能没有我的好朋友
But I need my best friend.
你跟我丈夫上床了
You slept with my husband.
别
Please.
我要去看下贝蒂
I'm going to go see Betty.
我要去看看我的朋友
I'm gonna see my friend.
-对不起  我取笑了阿历克斯  -我原谅你
-i'm sorry about teasing Alex.  -i forgive you.
-跟我聊聊外伤手术  -外伤?  即快又脏
-tell me about trauma surgery. -trauma? Quick and dirty.
我们没时间弄得好看点  没时间犯错
There's no time to make things pretty and no time for mistakes.
脱裤子  你要打一针头孢唑啉
Drop your pants. You need a shot of cefazolin i.M.
没时间犯错?
No time for mistakes,  huh?
那有怎样  你就没有出过错?
So what,  you don't make mistakes?
我只要出错  就是一条命
I make mistakes and people die.
我是我这个科里最好的外科医生...
I'm the best surgical resident in my program and...
我今天杀了个人  因为我没法给他缝合
Today I killed a man because I couldn't do a stitch.
在这行  尽你所能  倾你所有
In the field,  you do what you can,  you work with what you have.
我们是要做事
It's about something.
不是做最好  是要救命
It's not about being the best. It's about saving lives
我若犯错  就会死人  都是好小伙
I make mistakes. Guys die by my Hand,  good guys,
那些在沙漠里为祖国奋战的人
Guys who are fighting for their country in a desert.
我不可能无所不知  没有谁能做到
And I don't know everything. Nobody does.
我会出错  但我吸取教训
So I make mistakes,  and I learn.
下一次  我不会再犯同样的错误
And the next time,  I don't make that mistake again.
于是下次  另一个人  就会活下来
So theext time,  the next guy,  that guy,  he lives.
吃一堑  长一智
Mistakes are how you learn.
贝蒂  你觉得怎样了?
Hi,  Betty. How you feeling?
我的头...好痛
My head... Hurts.
发生了什么事?
What's going on?
贝蒂  你跟文森特都出了车祸
Betty,  you and Vincent were in a car accident.
文森特  我很遗憾他走了  贝蒂
Vincent... I'm sorry. I'm-i'm so sorry. He-he didn't make it,  Betty.
不  不  别
No,  no,  please.
不  他在另外一部车里  随时可能来  他是...
No.No. He's in the other car. He's just gonna be here any minute. He's...
我的头...
Oh... My head...
我头好痛  我是怎么了?
It hurts. What happened?
你现在看起来很稳定  是件好事
Well,  you look pretty stable,  which is good,
在你恢复之前体力
Because I can't let you go into your next
我不会给你安排手术
Surgery unless you're feeling strong and stable,  okay
人非圣贤  孰能无过
It happens. People make mistakes.
他们跟不该上床的人上床  然后隐瞒起来
You know,  they sleep with the wrong person and they hide it.
重要的是事情发生后
But if you ask me,  it's the part that comes
你怎么让它步回正道
After that matters,  the part where you make it right
我想你是有个好开始了
And I think you're off to a good start.
克莱夫  迈克尔 贝利尔准备好做剖腹探查术没?
Karev,  is Michael Briar ready for his ex lap?
一小时之前就准备好了
He was ready an hour ago.
我现在准备好了  给我预订手术室
And I'm ready now. Book the o.R.
好吧
Fine.
-克莱夫医生  现在几点了?  -现在是第二天
-dr. Karev,  what time is it?  -it's tomorrow.
他的医保失效了
His insurance expired.
对不起  弄伤了你的手
I'm sorry about the Hand.
这种事经常发生
These things happen.
都是因为我  如果你没有帮我挡 就会没事
Not to me they don't,  or they didn't before you existed for me.
在你出现之前  我还是很好的
Before you existed... I was good.
全院医生都想找我上台
Every doctor in this hospital wanted me in
因为我是很好的洗手护士
Their o.R. I was known as a damn good scrub nurse
可我现在成了疯女孩
And now I'm the crazy girl out of fatal
到处去刺外科医生
Attraction " who goes around stabbing surgeons.
对不起  我真的觉得...很抱歉
Sorry. I'm so... I'm sorry.
儿科有空缺  明天开始我到那里上班
There's an opening in peds. I start on their service tomorrow.
还有  你手的伤  真的很抱歉
Again,  very sorry about your Hand.
那...那我在这干嘛?
What's... What am I doing here?
文森特呢?
Where's Vincent?
发生了什么事?
Did something happen?
我不能再跟她说话了  我再也不会
I can't. I-i can't tell her anymore. I-i won't.
我知道
I know.
你们不如休息一下  然后再看看怎样
Why don't you two take a break,  check on things?
-我不想她孤零零一个人  -我在她旁边  没事
-i don't want her to be alone. -i'll sit with her. I don't mind.
我这是在医院吗?
Am I in a hospital?
亲爱的  发生了一起事故
Oh,  honey.. There's been an accident.
文森特在哪里?  他还好吗?
Where's Vincent? Is he okay?
你丈夫在来的路上  随时会到
Your husband is on his way. He'll be here any minute.
-他在来的路上了?  -是的
-he's on his way now?  -yes.
就快到了
He's just around the corner,  actually,
盯着门  他随时会出现
If you watch the door,  you'll see him any minute
-你会看见他的  -好 他正...
-you'll see him.  -good. He's...
-正在来的路上?  -正在来的路上
-he's on his way?  -he's on his way.
-快到了  -对 快到了
-around the corner.  -yes. He's around the corner.
这样对她好些
It's better for her.
谢谢
Thank you.
来  去看看我们的丈夫吧
Come on. Let's go check on our husbands.
克莱夫  我看那钟是坏了
Karev,  I think that clock is wrong.
显示凌晨2点半  但我肯定现在才11点58
I know it says 2:30 a.M. But I'm pretty sure it's actually only 11:58 p.M.
你能调对好吗?
Can you fix it,  please?
-把指针拨回?  -调回去
-set it back?  -set it back.
医院存档时间的准确性很重要
It's important that the official hospital record shows the right time,
保险公司也看重这点
And the insurance company needs it,  too.
而我认为现在才晚上11点58
And I say it's only 11:58 p.M..
手术刀
Scalpel
你很适合去战场
You know,  you'd be good in the field.
有了这个战争伤疤  你肯定能行
Now that you got this battle scar,  you'd fit right in.
-得了  -我是认真的
-oh, right.  -i'm serious.
你该放下包袱  动身去冒险
You should ditch this place and go for the adventure.
你说这里会让你激动  兴奋?
You're telling me this place gives you a rush,  a high?
是的  没错
Yeah. Yeah,  it does.
亨特医生  你在这
Oh,  dr. Hunt,  there you are.
腿部伤口怎么样?
How's the gash on that leg?
杨医生把我照顾得很好
Uh,  dr. Yang took good care of me,  excellent care.
我打了几个电话
I made a few calls
他们高度赞扬你在马里兰休克外伤科的表现
They speak very highly of you at maryland shock trauma.
我还听说了你在沙漠中用爆炸了的
I also heard a story that you constructed an o.R. Table
悍马做手术台  这是真的?
From an exploded humvee in the middle of the desert.That true?
在沙漠中得有点创新精神
Well,  you have to be innovative in the middle of the desert.
哪里都需要创新精神
You have to be innovative everywhere.
亨特医生  你觉得在这干怎么样?
How would you like a job,  dr. Hunt?
谢谢您的好意
I appreciate the offer,
但我还是回去挖伞兵坑  完成轮值
But I am due to go back to the sandpit,  finish my tour
祝你好运
Well... Good luck to you.
谢谢
Thanks.
怎么了?
What?
我甚至都不了解你
I-i... I-i don't even know you.
那又怎样?
So?
可能是降温治疗起了作用
Might have been the hypothermia treatment.
-或是我的医术  -谁知道呢
-or my surgical skills.  -oh,  we'll never know.
发生什么事了?
What's going on?
菲利普可以动脚趾头了
Phillip can wiggle his toes.
-说吧  -别叫我说
-oh,  say it.  -don't make me say it.
说吧  说给我听  即使技术上还没实现
Please say it. Say it for me. Even though it's technically not true yet.
我们让一个人能走路了
We made a man walk.
-我们让一个人能走路了  -我们让一个人能走路了
-we made a man walk.  -we made a man walk.
这样起床真舒服
What a nice way to wake up.
你跟梅瑞狄斯上过床了?
Did you sleep with Meredith?
-是呀  -为什么?
-yeah,  I did.  -why?
我意思是  抱歉  我...
I-i mean.Sor-i...
你爱过她?
Were you in love with her?
当时我想是的
I thought I was.
但我不敢承认  所以...我知道她
But I was too scared to admit it,  so i... I did know that she...
并不爱我...
Did not,  uh,  like me that way,  and...
我还是爱她  但我...
I did it anyway,  when I sh-i...
我本不该  因为我...
I shouldn't have,  because I'm...
此外只是...
Besides just being...
太自私了...我
So selfish,  i...
利用了她
You know,  to take advantage of her that way and to want her to want me
乘虚而入
Like that when clearly she d-
我去年犯了太多错误
Like I said,  I made a lot of mistakes last
我尽力回到正轨上来
Year,  but I'm trying to get back on track and..
我得自己处理
-you know,  I gotta do that by myself,
所以...  -唯一想帮你的原因是
So -the only reason i-i...I wanted to hel
我觉得我们不只是室友
Is because i-i-i feel like you and I are more than just...Roommates.
我们不只是室友
We are more than just roommates.
那我们是?
We are?
是朋友
Yeah,  we're friends. I mean,
你现在是我的知己了
Right now you're probably one of my best friends
知己
Best friends.
我不是个试验者
I'm not an experimenter.
我不想做试验
I don't like to experiment.
但你出现了  我们一起试验
But then you showed up,  and we did it together,
而试验成功了
And the experiment was kind of a success.
我以前没试过  吻女孩
Look,  I've never done this before. I-i've never kissed a girl.
不知道是否喜欢吻女孩们
I'm not sure I even like kissing girls.
事实上  我不喜欢吻女孩们
I don't,  actually,  like kissing girls.
我只喜欢吻一个女孩
I just... Like kissing one girl.
就是你
You.
我没参照物可对比...
I don't have anything to compare it with.I...
你是我吻过的唯一女性
You're the only woman I've ever kissed.
你也害怕了?
So you're freaking out,  too?
-去看了很久心理医生  -看心理医生对我也没用
-a lot of therapy time.  -yeah,  I don't do therapy.
我只觉得好震惊  又很怀念...
I just get all "aah!" and then I get all clingy and...
这些还不必让你知道
Okay. You don't need to know that yet.
这样我们算不算"处女"了?
So... Does this.. This kinda makes us virgins,  doesn't it?
我想某些程度上是的
I... Guess in a way it does.
处女
Virgins.
我们可以一起害怕啊
Hey,  we can be scared together.
某种程度上还是处女了  一起害怕吧
Kind of virgins,  and,  yeah,  we can be scared together.
-好了?  -谢谢
-okay?  -yeah,  thanks.
你说我和德里克不会有结果
You said Derek and I would never make it.
我为胡说八道而遭了报应
And then I was karmically impaled for saying it.
你说的对  人们不会幸福快乐的过一辈子
But you're right. I mean,  people don't really have happily ever afters.
甚至很少会有结果
People barely have ever afters.
我和他又怎么能例外?
So why would Derek and I be any different?
梅瑞为什么要介意我的想法?
Mere,  why do you care what I think?
因为你是我的人
Because you're my person.
而且如果我要为了他-
And if I'm gonna do this with him-
做个健康
Be whole and healthy and be a warm,
温情的闺蜜  我需要你
Gooey person who lives with a boy,  I need you
我需要你上场  为我打气
I need you on board. I need you to cheer me on.
因为你是唯一懂我...
Because you're the only one who knows me...
真的在内心深处很暗的地方都懂
Darkly,  really knows me.
我需要你假装我可以做得到  即使连你都不信
I need you to pretend that I can do this,  even if you don't believe.
因为如果你抛弃我  我会坚持不下去的
Because if you abandon me now,  I will never make it,
永远也不会有好结果  只是过着...
And I'll never get my happy ending,  and then that's just-
人生
Life.
我求你啦
I'm saying please here.
我认为你和德里克会有好结果  你会做到的
I think you and Derek will make it. You'll make it work.
你光捡好听的说?
Are you just telling me what I want to hear?
我是你的人  站在你这边
I am your person. I'm on your side.
很久很久以前
Once upon a time...
幸福美满的生活在一起
Happily ever after...
故事讲的都是做梦才有的
The stories we tell are the stuff of dreams.
童话是不会成真的
Fairy tales don't come true.
我说了会给你看裙子的
See? I told you I would show you my dress.
你看上去比新娘还美
You look better than a bride.
现实总是更残酷...
Reality is much stormier...
更黑暗...
Much murkier...
更可怕
Much scarier.
大家听着
Listen up,  people.
听着
Listen up.
我们原本是西部最好的外科诊疗机构
We used to be the best surgical program in the West,
最好的  新崛起的
An upstart program that no one ever
令人震惊的好医院
Heard of that blew everyone out the water
而一夜之间
Then overnight,  we got old..
我们变老  邋遢  泯然众人矣
Entrenched and sloppy,  just like everyone else
我们一直在吃老本
We've been resting on our laurels.
你们都失去了创新精神
You have all been failing- failing to take initiative,
问不出苛刻的问题  练不出熟练技巧
Failing to ask the tough questions,  failing to practice your skills,
未能提供锻炼技巧的机会
Failing to give opportunity to practice skills.
而我放任此事发生
And I let it happen.
不是你们失败了  是我们都失败了
So you have not failed. We have failed.
现在要停止这种状况
Well,  it stops,  and it stops now.
人们偏重心外科和脑外科
People sliding over general surgery as though they will never see anything
好像普外科没他们事情一样
But a heart or a brain through the course of their career,
好像血经过心脏不会流到身体
As though blood from the heart doesn't make its way through the whole body
神经也不会传递到脑干
Or the nerves don't travel past the brain stem.
这是差劲的教学  教出的是差劲的外科医生
It's shoddy teaching,  and it makes for shoddy surgeons.
我们都失败了
We've failed.
懂了吗?
Get it?
我们都失败了  现在要停止
We all have,  and it stops now.
外科训练草案正式改变了
The surgical training protocol is officially changing,  people.
门槛已经提高了
The bar has been raised.
你们都给我注意了
Consider yourself on notice.
现实  比幸福美满生活在一起有趣多了
Reality-it's so much more interesting than living happily ever after.